A Guide to the Additional Papers of Alan Cheuse, 1975-1989
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Papers of Alan Cheuse 1975-1989
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10726-f,-g
This collection consists of ca. 1,180 items (6 Hollinger boxes, 2 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Alan Cheuse of Fairfax, Virginia, placed his papers on loan to the Library on October 27, 1989, and January 4, 1990. The papers were purchased by the Library on September 11, 2003.
Scope and Content Information
These additions to the papers of Alan Cheuse consists of ca. 1,180 items (6 Hollinger boxes, 2 linear feet), 1975-1989, and contains correspondence, typescripts and printed copies of book reviews, short stories, articles, a page proof of Fall Out of Heaven, audio cassettes, a videotape, research material, printed material, newsclippings, photographs, financial documents, and other miscellaneous material.
The correspondence series consists of professional, literary, and personal letters and postcards. The postcards have been physically separated from the rest of the correspondence but are included in the list of correspondents following the abbreviation PC.
The second series comprises manuscripts of articles, short stories, reviews, and page proofs of Fall Out of Heaven, by Alan Cheuse, including the printed version of the manuscript present in the collection. These are single foldered in alphabetical order by title and listed separately in the box listing part of this guide.
The third series contains miscellaneous papers such as financial documents, research notes, photographs, printed programs, invitations, broadsides, and newsclippings, reviews of Cheuse's books The Bohemians, Fall Out of Heaven, and Candace and Other Stories, a video cassette recording, cassette tapes, and writing by other authors. Of special note is the manuscript for "An Introduction to Alan Cheuse" written and signed by George Garrett.
Correspondents include: Rudolfo A. Anaya, 1989 Jan 30; Barbara Lazear Ascher, 1989 Jun 22; Madison Smartt Bell, 1988 Sep 19; Gina Berriault, 1988 Jul 22; Roy Blount, Jr. 1988 Jul 26; Frederick Buechner, 1988 Aug 24; Fred Busch, 1989 Apr 27; Josephine Carson, 1981 Oct 26; 1988 Oct 23; Nicholas Delbanco, 1981 Nov 18; 1989 Aug 18; n.d.; PC - 1988 Dec 9; 1989 Aug 15; Robb Forman Dew, 1986 May 3; Annie Dillard, 1986 Feb 11; 1989 May 5; n.d.; PC - 1989 Sep 20; [1989 ante Sep 6]; E.L. Doctorow, 1988 Nov 11; Rita Dove, 1989 Feb 28; Richard Elman, 1985 Feb 26, Mar 10, Sep 6; 1986 Jan 6, Feb 5; 1989 Apr 12, Jun 12; n.d.; Cheri Fein, 1989 Apr 27; George Garrett, 1985 Jan 21, Sep 30; 1989 Apr 29, Sep 1 and 11, Oct 2 and 13; Herbert Gold, 1984 Nov 14; 1985 May 31; 1986 Mar 25; 1989 Jan 4, [Apr 22]; PC - 1989 Jan 19; Allan Gurganus, 1989 Aug 12; PC - 1988 Dec 22; William J. Holinger, 1988 Oct 4; James D. Houston, 1983 Dec 12; 1984 Dec 27; 1986 Feb 1; William Kennedy, 1989 Sep 26; James Howard Kunstler, 1988 Sep 30, Oct 12; 1989 May 9, Jun 5; Barry Lopez, 1984 Dec 13; 1989 Mar 19, Jul 26, Sep 15; Richard McCann, 1988 Oct 26; PC - 1989 Apr 18; Terry McMillan, 1989 Aug 3; PC - 1989 Feb 9, Oct 14; Mitch Markowitz, 1988 Dec 5; n.d.; PC - 1981 Mar 6; 1984 Oct 16; 1985 Feb 1; Wright Morris, 1988 Dec 27; Peter Najarian, 1989 Sep 11; Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis, 1988 Oct 11; Carolyn Page, 1989 Aug 30; Victor Perera, 1985 Feb 21, May 8; PC - 1984 Jan 4 and 25; 1985 Apr 6; Robert Pinsky, 1988 Dec 11; Lynne Sharon Schwartz, 1988 Dec 9; Mary Lee Settle, PC - 1989 Aug 7; Darcey Steinke, 1988 Jun 11, Jul 22, Nov 9; 1989 Jan 1, Jun 20, Jul 8, n.d.; PC - 1988 Nov 28; 1989 Jul 7; William L. Tazewell, PC - 1989 Aug 21; Richard Tillinghast, 1985 Apr 8; PC - 1989 Aug 5; John Updike, 1988 Dec 14; Allen Wier, 1989 Jun 6 and 19, Aug 30, Sep 28, Oct 25; Jon Manchip White, 1985 Feb 22; PC - 1989 May 22; Jun 24; Kate Woodworth, 1989 Jul 10; Tobias Wolff, 1985 Apr 27; 1986 May 24; 1988 Nov 6; 1989 Apr 6 and 22; Jonathan Yardley, 1985 Feb 24; Al Young, 1984 Dec 28; 1988 Jul 29
Subjects include: Herbert Gold, 1981 Oct 26; Cormac McCarthy and John Updike 1985 Mar 12; Miami, Florida Riots 1989 Jan 18; John Reed, 1981 Oct 26; John Steinbeck, 1983 Dec 12; Bob Thompson, (1937-1965), black painter 1985 Feb 5; Anne Tyler, 1988 Dec 14
Contents List
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE
  - Correspondence (7 folders) 1980-1989 Jun (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (3 folders) 1989 Jul-Oct, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence re California Employment 1981 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence re Proposals for Articles, Etc. 1975-1983 (Box 2)
  - Letters from Publishers re Book Reviews 1980-1984 (Box 2)
  - Postcards and Notecards (2 folders) 1981, 1984-1989, n.d. (Box 2)
- SERIES II: MANUSCRIPTS BY ALAN CHEUSE
  - "Accident" n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  - "All My Troubles Seemed So Far Away" n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  - "The Book of Life and the Book of Death" n.d., 2 TMs (Box 3)
  - "Bottomless in the Bible Belt" n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  - "Bringing Home the Gold: Symbolic Technique in B. Traven's The Treasures of the Sierra Madre" n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  - "The Buzzer Box" n.d., 3 TMs (Box 3)
  - "Chicano Mirrors" 1981, TMs (Box 3)
  - "Chile Settles Down For a Long Winter's Nap" 1982, 2 TMs (Box 3)
  - "Country Artisan's Gallery" in The New York Times1983, 2 TMs and Print (Box 3)
  - "Daughters of the Eighties" n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  - "Deserters" n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  - "Draper Books Offers A Home For Literature In the Buckle of the Bible Belt" 1982-1983, TMs and Print (Box 3)
  - "Evasion" n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  - Fall Out of Heaven(Uncorrected), Review Copy 1987 Sep, Page Proof (Box 3)
  - "Foreign Wars" 1981, TMs (Box 3)
  - "Garden of the Gods" n.d., 3 TMs (Box 3)
  - "Georgina and the Golden Goat," a Short Screenplay Treatment by Jon Manchip White and Alan Cheuse n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  - "His Name is Chaim Potok" in Present Tense1984, Print (Box 4)
  - "Home Work" in The Boston Sunday Globe1979, Print (Box 4)
  - Introductions for Nicholas Delbanco and Thomas Keneally 1988-1989, 2 TMs (Box 4)
  - "It's Not Easy Being A Man Today" in Ladies Home Journalca. 1982, 2 TMs (Box 4)
  - Journal kept by Alan Cheuse for a week 1989 Jan, TMs (Box 4)
  - "Kismet" n.d., 4 TMs (Box 4)
  - "Liberal's Progress: The Quest Narratives of Peter Matthiessen" n.d., 2 TMs (Box 4)
  - "Little America" in The New York Times1982, 2 TMs (Box 4)
  - "Man In a Barrel" 1989 May, TMs (Box 4)
  - "Nights on the Cumberland Plateau" n.d., 2 TMs (Box 4)
  - "Oasis in Appalachia" in The New York Times1985 Oct, Print (Box 4)
  - "Odi et Amo: The State of the Book Review in the U.S. Today" 1980, TMs (Box 4)
  - "On Point," an Outline for a Screenplay based on a story by Katherine Shirek and Alan Cheuse 1983, 3 TMs (Box 4)
  - "On the Tram" n.d., 2 TMs (Box 4)
  - "The Pac-Man Murders" n.d., 2 TMs (Box 4)
  - "Portrait of the Artist As a Post-Columbian Artifact: The Adventurous Asceticism of Evan Connell" n.d., TMs (Box 4)
  - Reviews by Alan Cheuse, arranged alphabetically by title of book (2 folders) 1983-1989, n.d. (Box 4)
  - "Slides" n.d., 2 TMs (Box 4)
  - "Sources of Country Music" ca. 1985, TMs (Box 4)
  - "The Tennessee Waltz" n.d., 5 TMs (Box 5)
  - "That Was Then, This is Now: The Opry, Old But Not So Grand" 1983, TMs (Box 5)
  - "Things My Mother Never Taught Me" in The Ladies Home Journal1981, 2 TMs and Print (Box 5)
  - "Toward Easter Island" n.d., 3 TMs and Print (Box 5)
  - "Trail-Blazers and Bee-Hunters: A Comparative View of the Affinities Between North American and Latin American Literary Culture" (Lecture) 1980, 1982, TMs (Box 5)
  - "TVA Turns Fifty: America's Unique Public Corporation Celebrates Its Golden Anniversary" in The Boston Globe1983, 2 TMs (Box 5)
  - "Two Hundred Years of Solitude: The Sad History of North American, Latin American Literary Relations" 1980, TMs (Box 5)
  - "Winter In a Certain State" (Incomplete) n.d., TMs (Box 5)
- SERIES III: MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS
  - "An Introduction to Alan Cheuse" by George Garrett, including the printed version n.d., TMsS (Box 5)
  - Barbara Mandrell Research 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Photographs 1981-1989, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Newsclippings ca. 1988-1989 (Box 5)
  - Printed Material (2 folders) 1981-1989, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Reviews re The Bohemians by Alan Cheuse ca. 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Reviews re Candace and Other Stories and Fall Out of Heaven by Alan Cheuse 1983 and 1989 (Box 6)
  - Royalties and Other Financial Documents ca. 1981-1989 (Box 6)
  - John Steinbeck Research 1983 (Box 6)
  - Writing by Other Authors (2 folders) 1984-1989, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Perth Amboy High School Hall of Fame Induction Ceremony. Videocassette recording (VC 15) 1989 (Box 6)
  - Alan Cheuse reading at "Booked for Lunch," at Ann Arbor, Michigan. Audiocassette recording (T-900) 1985 Jan 8 (Box 6)
  - Alan Cheuse Appearance on "Good Evening From Minnesota," with Noah Adams, M[innesota ?] Public Radio. Audiocassette recording (T-901) 1987 Nov 7 (Box 6)